onlinecolleges.net 2018-04-04

# Privacy Policy | OnlineColleges.net

_Terms of Use and Privacy Policy for Use of OnlineColleges.net (Effective January 6, 2016)_

Thank you for visiting OnlineColleges.net and utilizing our content and services. This page will explain the conditions under which you may utilize our website, and the methods OnlineColleges.net employs to gather and use different types of information so that we may provide the content and related products and services users require. 

By using our website, you are agreeing to the following Terms of Use and Privacy Policy. You acknowledge and agree that information collected on OnlineColleges.net may be shared with schools, affiliated companies, and third parties for the purpose of providing you with information about degrees, programs, and other education-related products and services in which you have expressed interest. You also acknowledge and agree that we retain the right to release any collected information — including personally identifiable information — as needed to businesses providing our company with administrative services, such as an email delivery service.

By voluntarily submitting personal information to OnlineColleges.net, you are granting permission for us, our affiliated entities — including schools, third party marketing partners, and vendors — to contact you through methods including via telephone, text messages, email, or mail for the purpose of providing information — including marketing — for education-related products and services. In addition, through this action, you grant us — including our affiliates, partners, and vendors — the right to contact you for a period of time. This will relinquish any rights granted to you by the Do Not Call list or other applicable law. Effectively, by submitting personal information on this website, you omit yourself from the Do Not Call requirements established by state and federal governments, and may exempt us from other applicable laws.

We also retain the right to release your personal information in circumstances where it is required by law. An example of such a circumstance is to abide by a subpoena or other legal procedure, when, in good faith, we believe it is necessary to preserve our rights, to ensure the safety of you or others, to explore alleged fraud, to reply to a government or legal request, and/or in the instance that OnlineColleges.net is merging, acquisitioning, or selling some or all of its assets to a third party.

## Types of Information Collected

### Submitted information

Submitted information is the voluntary submission of personal contact information (such as name, telephone number, mailing address, and email address), as well any other information that may have been required to match you to an education product or service. This is typically collected through a web form that users fill out. We collect, store, and share this information with schools and other third parties as necessary to provide you with relevant information about schools, programs, and education-related services.

By submitting this information, you authorize OnlineColleges.net and our affiliated schools and partners to contact you in accordance with all applicable laws by telephone, text message, email, or mail regarding education options or related topics. However, if you receive any email communications from us, a school, or third party, you can unsubscribe through a link in the email, at which point you will be removed from the mailing list of that sender.

### Automatic information

Automatic information is data collected and stored whenever users interact with OnlineColleges.net. This is anonymous information and include, but are not limited to, your browser version, operating system version, and your IP address. This information is useful for helping us improve the website and create a more relevant user experience. To collect this automatic data, we use “cookies” to gather the data for analytics, site optimization, and for tailored advertising and marketing purposes. 

#### Cookie Policy

By using this website, you acknowledge that OnlineColleges.net uses cookies and consent to our use of cookies.

Cookies are small pieces of data sent from a website and stored in the user’s web browser. These are used for technical purposes, such as web analytics. OnlineColleges.net’s web analytics are mainly performed using Google Analytics, a tool provided by Google, Inc. Advertising cookies — sometimes referred to as third-party cookies because they track navigation and publish ads on behalf of third parties — do not contain personally identifiable information, allowing users to remain anonymous. They do, however, enable advertisers to make ads more relevant to the user’s interests. For more information about Google Analytics, check [Google’s privacy policy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245).

Below are examples of how cookies may be used by us, including through services and partnerships with vendors and third-party service providers:

  * “Lead auditing” to ensure the accuracy, relevance, and validity of submitted information
  * Web analytics that include demographic and other anonymous data for web optimization and other analysis
  * Marketing and conversion tracking cookies, used for — but are not limited to — targeting and optimizing digital ad serving to improve relevance, user experience, and advertising effectiveness

You can remove cookies through your browser settings at any time. However, you may need to do this on a per use basis. You can also generally opt out of receiving personalized ads from third-party advertisers and ad networks that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) or that follow the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. To do so, visit the opt-out pages on the NAI website and DAA websites.

## Terms of Use and Privacy Policy Changes Notification

It is possible that in the future, we will revise our Terms of Use and Privacy Policy if we change our practices. To remain up-to-date on our policies, we recommend that you revisit this page periodically.

If you have any questions or concerns about this Terms of Use and Privacy Policy, please use our contact form.
